What's the oldest meal you've eaten?
你吃过的最古老的食物是什么？
Maybe you've had leftovers from a few days ago.
也许你吃过几天前的剩菜。
They probably still tasted good.
它们的味道可能仍然不错。
But what if it wasn't a few days ago, what if you ate a 60-day old stew?
但如果那不是几天前，而是炖了60天的炖菜呢？
Or a 49-year-old beef noodle soup?
或者是49年的牛肉面汤？
Perpetual stew is a dish that is never taken off the heat; it's never finished.
永续炖菜是一道从不关火的菜肴；它永远不会被吃完。
As portions are served, new ingredients are put in the pot to replace them.
当一部分被盛出后，新的食材会被放入锅中取代它们。
One day's stew becomes the basis of the following days' meals.
一天的炖菜成为接下来几天餐食的基础。
There have been some famous examples.
有一些著名的例子。
This year, Annie Rauwerda's 60-day stew became a social media sensation.
今年，安妮·劳维尔达的60天炖菜成为社交媒体上轰动一时的事件。
One Bangkok restaurant claims to have been cooking its beef noodle soup since the 1970s.
曼谷一家餐厅声称自20世纪70年代以来一直在烹饪其牛肉面汤。
It has been suggested that perpetual stew was a tradition in Medieval Europe when the effort required to start a fire meant that they were left to burn all day, and a pot of stew was always simmering away on top of it.
有人认为，永续炖菜是中世纪欧洲的一种传统，当时生火需要付出很大努力，这意味着火会整天燃烧，一锅炖菜总是在火上慢炖着。
One New York Times article tells us about a stew in Normandy that was kept cooking for 300 years.
《纽约时报》的一篇文章告诉我们，诺曼底有一道炖菜持续烹饪了300年。
This tradition may date back to the Middle Ages, but thankfully, our understanding of food hygiene has developed since then.
这一传统可能追溯到中世纪，但值得庆幸的是，自那时起我们对食品卫生的理解一直在进步中。
In a world where food is often thrown away once it reaches its use-by date, many people have asked how safe perpetual stew can actually be.
在一个食物一旦达到保质期就常被丢弃的世界里，许多人都在问永续炖菜到底有多安全。
Experts are divided, some maintain that as long as the stew is kept bubbling away at a temperature too high for pathogens to survive, it should be safe.
专家们意见不一，一些人坚持认为，只要炖菜保持沸腾状态，温度高到病原体无法生存，就应该是安全的。
Others suggest that meat can become dangerous if it's left in the stew for too long.
另一些人则认为，如果肉在炖菜中放置太久，可能会变得危险。
Concerns have also been raised that some vegetables, such as potatoes, or those containing nitrates, could become more toxic the more they are reheated.
也有人提出担忧，一些蔬菜，比如土豆或含有硝酸盐的蔬菜，随着反复加热可能会变得毒性更强。
Advocates of slow cooking believe that the best food takes time, but even they may be surprised by a months or years-old perpetual stew.
慢炖饮食的倡导者相信最好的食物需要时间，但即使是他们，也可能会对炖了数月或数年的永续炖菜感到惊讶。